<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XBRL on Redwall Analytics Blogsite</title>
    <link>/tags/xbrl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XBRL on Redwall Analytics Blogsite</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
=======
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
>>>>>>> 527a5d77148ed8052e6e35819cdb0a8e21c3eefd
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/xbrl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <title>Tabulizer and pdftools togeteher as Super-powers - Part 2</title>
      <link>/2020/04/06/tabulizer-and-pdftools-togeteher-as-super-powers-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/06/tabulizer-and-pdftools-togeteher-as-super-powers-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post will be a continuation of Parsing of Mass Municipal PDF CAFR’s with Tabulizer, pdftools and AWS Textract - Part 1 dealing with extracting data from PDFs using R. When Redwall discovered pdftools, and its pdf_data function, which maps out every word on a pdf page by x-y coordinate, we thought that was interesting, but didn’t really know how to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing Mass Municipal PDF CAFRs with Tabulizer, pdftools and AWS Textract - Part 1</title>
      <link>/2020/03/31/parsing-mass-municipal-pdf-cafrs-with-tabulizer-pdftools-and-aws-textract-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/31/parsing-mass-municipal-pdf-cafrs-with-tabulizer-pdftools-and-aws-textract-part-1/</guid>
=======
      <title>Parsing of Mass Municipal PDF CAFR&#39;s with Tabulizer, pdftools and AWS Textract - Part 1</title>
      <link>/code_based/parsing-of-mass-municipal-pdf-cafr-s-with-the-center-for-municipal-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code_based/parsing-of-mass-municipal-pdf-cafr-s-with-the-center-for-municipal-finance/</guid>
>>>>>>> 527a5d77148ed8052e6e35819cdb0a8e21c3eefd
      <description>Introduction Redwall Analytics had the pleasure of collaborating with Marc Joffe, of Reason Foundation, in its October 2018 post Replicating Yankee Institute Risk Score Over 15 Years for 150 Connecticut towns. This involved taking a well organized public dataset from the State’s website, and analyzing it in R. When Marc called to ask if we could report on our blog site about similar analysis for 150 Massachusetts towns, as in Connecticut’s Warning Signs, we jumped at the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk Though of Accessing Financial Statements with XBRL in R - Part 1</title>
      <link>/2020/02/18/a-walk-though-of-accessing-financial-statements-with-xbrl-in-r-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/18/a-walk-though-of-accessing-financial-statements-with-xbrl-in-r-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As financial professionals and analytic software lovers, the ability to efficiently load a large number of financial statements, and conduct an analysis has always been a key objective. In previous posts, Redwall Analytics worked with a 15-year time series of municipal Comprehensive Annual Financial Reports (CAFR) for 15 Fairfield County, CT towns Fairfield County Town Level Spending and Liabilities Gallop Since 2001. We also studied the worrisome long-term, time series of unfunded liabilities for all 169 Connecticut municipalities Connecticut City Unfunded Pension And OPEB Liabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking R&amp;D spending by 700 Listed US Pharma Companies - Part 2</title>
      <link>/2020/02/18/tracking-r-d-spending-by-700-listed-us-pharma-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/18/tracking-r-d-spending-by-700-listed-us-pharma-companies/</guid>
      <description># Re-load data previously stored for purposes of this blog post pharma &amp;lt;- fread(&amp;quot;~/Desktop/David/Projects/xbrl_investment/data/pharma_inc.csv&amp;quot;) Introduction In A Walk Though of Accessing Financial Statements with XBRL in R - Part 1, we went through the first steps of pulling XBRL data for a single company from Edgar into R. Although an improvement over manual plugging of numbers into a Excel, there is still a way to go to having clean comparable numbers, and several of challenges were discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>